Guide to the Council of School Superintendents records, 1883-1967.
Council of School Superintendents records, 1883-1967
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Council of School Superintendents records, 1883-1967.
2750
Council of School Superintendents, Cities and Villages, State of New York.
5.5 cubic ft.,
Minutes, financial records, correspondence, audiotape, transcript, microfilm, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes of annual meetings, committee files and financial records, correspondence, membership lists of the Council of School Superintendents. Also, tape and transcript of round table discussion conducted by Sam Bishop, January 17, 1967; and one reel of negative microfilm of Enna Smith Burdick's "Edward Smith, Syracuse Schoolmaster," M.S. thesis, 1940, Syracuse University.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Council of School Superintendents merged with the Association of School District Administrators of New York State on September 1, 1967. The new organization was named the New York State Council of School District Administrators.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes of annual meetings, committee files and financial records, correspondence, membership lists of the Council of School Superintendents. Also, tape and transcript of round table discussion conducted by Sam Bishop, January 17, 1967; and one reel of negative microfilm of Enna Smith Burdick's "Edward Smith, Syracuse Schoolmaster," M.S. thesis, 1940, Syracuse University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Council of School Superintendents, Cities and Villages, State of New York.; Bishop, Sam.; Burdick, Enna Smith.; Smith, Edward.; Association of School District Administrators of New York State.; New York State Council of School District Administrators.
Subjects:
Education--School superintendents.
Places:
New York (State)--Syracuse.
Form and Genre Terms:
Theses.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Annual Meetings, 1883-1967
  - Folders labeled chronologically, "Annual Meetings," from 1883 through 1967 (Box 1)
  - Also, inserted chronologically are folders labeled "Misc." for the following years:
    - 1901 (Box 1)
    - 1903 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
    - 1909 (Box 1)
    - 1911 (Box 1)
    - 1913 (Box 1)
    - 1926 (Box 1)
    - 1927 (Box 1)
    - 1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931 (Box 1)
    - 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1938 (Box 1)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1950 (Box 1)
    - 1951 (Box 1)
    - 1953 (Box 1)
    - 1954 (Box 1)
    - 1955 (Box 1)
    - 1956 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1962 (Box 1)
    - Undated misc. (Box 1)
- Council Committees
  - List of Committees (Box 2)
  - NYS Council CAL (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Comm. Compensating Teachers (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Commissioner's Council (Box 2)
  - Administrative Leadership (Box 2)
  - NYS Council List of Committees, Program for Grossinger's, List of Supts. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Comm. on Info. and Hospitality (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Exec. Committee (Box 2)
  - Data Processing (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Higher Education Comm. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Legislative Committee (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Gross. Planning Com. Comm. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Program Committee (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Physical Fitness (Box 2)
  - Relationship and Responsibility of State Educ. Dept. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Research Committee (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Resolutions Committee (Box 2)
  - NYS Review and Report on Candidates for Office in A.A.S.A. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council on Rural Educ. (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Secretary (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Treasurer (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Grossingers Conference (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Minutes Business Meetings (Box 2)
  - Reimbursements (items) from NYSCSS to District 6 (Box 2)
  - Vouchers (Box 2)
  - "New Ideas" Booklet (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Budget (Box 2)
  - NYS Council, Grossinger's 1964 (Box 2)
  - Convention, Jan. 1963, Grossinger's (Box 2)
  - NYS. Supt. Atlantic City (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Supts Convention, Sept. 1962 Concord (Box 2)
  - NYS Council Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- NYS Council
  - Constitution (Box 2)
  - Contract for Saranac Inn (Box 2)
  - Finances (Box 2)
  - Executive Sessions 1957-1959 (Box 2)
  - General Meetings, 1958-1961 (Box 2)
  - Dec. 1960 Meeting (Box 2)
  - Saranac Meeting, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous - Saranac Conf. (Box 2)
  - Sunday Evening - Saranac (Box 2)
  - Monday Morning - Saranac (Box 2)
  - Tuesday Evening - Saranac, Banquet (Box 2)
  - Ten Eyck Hotel (Box 2)
  - AASA Meeting, St. Louis, Apr. 1966 (Box 2)
  - AASA Meeting, Chicago, May 5-7, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Past Presidents (Box 2)
  - New Superintendents, 1960 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - Possible Locations for Fall Meeting (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 2)
  - James E. Allen (Box 2)
  - Treasurer (Box 2)
  - Secretary - Ed. L. Osborn (Box 2)
  - Cy Seymour (Box 2)
  - Philip Wyckoff (Box 2)
- Committees
  - Committee Lists (Box 2)
  - Commissioner's Special Council (Box 2)
  - Administrative Leadership (Box 2)
  - AASA Committee (Box 2)
  - Brochure (Box 2)
  - Executive Session (Box 2)
  - Evaluation of Conferences (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee (Box 2)
  - Gifted Children Comm., NYSTA (Box 2)
  - Golf Committee (Box 2)
  - Ladies' Entertainment Committee (Box 2)
  - Legislative Committee (Box 2)
  - Committee on Merging Dist. Supts and Supts (Box 2)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 2)
  - NYSTA (Box 2)
  - Press Relations Committee (Box 2)
  - Professional Practices and Ethics Committee (Box 2)
  - Program Committee (Box 2)
  - Research Committee (Box 2)
  - Rural Education (Box 2)
  - Resolutions, 1954-1960 (Box 2)
  - Resolution, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Secretarial Status Committee (Box 2)
  - State Dept. Admin. Relationship Comm. (Box 2)
  - King vs. Ambellian (Box 2)
  - Scholastic Record Kindergarten (Box 2)
  - Scholastic Record 7-12 (Box 2)
  - Teacher Education and Certification (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Unfiled Material (Box 2)
- Financial
  - Folders labeled chronologically, "Financial," from 1933 through 1956 (Box 2)
- Other files
  - Painter Conference (Box 3)
  - Rochester Banquet (Box 3)
  - NYS Council Committees (Box 3)
  - NYS 1965-1966 Committees (Box 3)
  - NYS County Supts. Committees - a (Box 3)
  - NYS County Supts. Committees - b (Box 3)
  - NYS County Supts. Committees - c (Box 3)
  - General Correspondence, Sept. 1, 1964-Jan. 1, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Council of Supts. Committees (Box 3)
  - Auditing (Box 3)
  - Nominations (Box 3)
  - Photography (Box 3)
  - Recreation (Box 3)
  - Resolutions (Box 3)
  - Council of Supts. Jan. 1964 Meeting (Box 3)
  - Council of Supts. Vouchers - Approved, Fiscal Year 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Council of School Supts. Vouchers - Approved, Fiscal Year 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Grossinger's Supt. Meeting, Fall 1963 (Box 3)
  - Record of 1963 Memberships (Box 3)
  - Council of School Supts Financial Reports of Fiscal Year 1961-1962, Council of School Supts Correspondence, 1962-1963; Council of School Supts Financial Statement, 1962-1963; Council of School Supts Vouchers - Approved, Current Year 1962-1963 - a; Council of School Supts Vouchers - Approved, Current Year 1962-1963 - b; Council of School Supts Vouchers - Approved, Current Year 1962-1963 - c (Box 3)
  - Checklists (Box 3)
  - Membership lists, Invitations to New Supts, Letters to late members (Box 3)
  - Memberships, Resignations, Deaths, etc. (Box 3)
  - Membership Lists, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Memberships, 1963-1964 - a, Correspondence, Memberships, 1963-1964 - b (Box 3)
  - Membership Lists Current (Box 3)
  - Checking Account Statements, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Income Tax, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Checking Account - old, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Saranac Inn Meeting, Fall 1961 (Box 3)
  - Checking Accounts, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Ticket Requests (Box 3)
  - Luncheon, Jan. 31, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Dinners (Box 3)
  - Dinner, Feb. 17, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Budgets - Previous years (Box 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1963-1964 - a (Box 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1963-1964 - b (Box 3)
  - Fall Meeting, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Superintendents, 1965-1966 - a (Box 4)
  - Superintendents, 1965-1966 - b (Box 4)
  - Superintendents, 1965-1966 - c (Box 4)
  - Superintendents, 1965-1966 - d (Box 4)
  - Superintendents, 1965-1966 - e (Box 4)
  - Albany Meeting, Jan. 20, 1967 (Box 4)
  - NYS Council of Supts., Affiliated Organizations (Box 4)
  - AASA Membership Committee (Box 4)
  - Auditing Committee (Box 4)
  - Jt. Committee on Athletics Controversy - a (Box 4)
  - Jt. Committee on Athletics Controversy - b (Box 4)
  - Budget and Finance, 1965-1966 - a (Box 4)
  - Budget and Finance, 1965-1966 - b (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention Committee - a (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention Committee - b (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention Committee - c (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention Committee - d (Box 4)
  - Representatives to CAL Legis. Council (Box 4)
  - Commissioner's Advisory Council (Box 4)
  - Compensating Teacher Competency (Box 4)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 4)
  - Data Processing Committee (Box 4)
  - Distinguished Service Award (Box 4)
  - Education & Human Rights Committee (Box 4)
  - Committee on Hospitality (Box 4)
  - General, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
  - Legislative Committees (Box 4)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 4)
  - Perkins Report on Educational Leadership (Box 4)
  - Relationships - School Boards - State Education Dept. (Box 4)
  - Reorganization Study Committee (Box 4)
  - Rural Education Committee (Box 4)
  - Principal's Salary Law (Box 4)
  - Program Committee (Box 4)
  - Committee on Research and Innovations (Box 4)
  - Resolutions Committee (Box 4)
  - School District Administrators (Box 4)
  - State Leadership Conference, Summer 1966 (Box 4)
  - Textbook Law Implementation Committee (Box 4)
  - Program - Jt. Conference, Sept. 1965 (Box 4)
  - Business Meeting - a (Box 4)
  - Business Meeting - b (Box 4)
  - Annual Conference, 1966 - a (Box 4)
  - Annual Conference, 1966 - b (Box 4)
  - Annual Conference, 1966. Executive Meeting (Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Banquet - Grossingers, Sept. 27, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Time and Place Committee, 1968 Convention (Box 4)
- Dr. Earl Soper papers
  - AASA Atlantic City, Feb. 1967 (Box 5)
  - AASA Memberships, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Eastern Seaboard Conference, [1967] (Box 5)
  - AASA National Assessment, [1967] (Box 5)
  - AASA Chicago, Apr. 1966 (Box 5)
  - AASA Chicago, Apr. 1967 (Box 5)
  - Atlantic City, Feb. 1966 (Box 5)
  - Council of Supts., 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Council of Supts., 1959-1963 (Box 5)
  - Council of Supts., Mar. 1964 (Box 5)
  - CAL (Council for Administrative Leadership), [1967] (Box 5)
  - Council of Supts. Distinguished Service Award, [1965] (Box 5)
  - Grossingers (Annual Meeting), 1967 (Box 5)
  - Recreation [Changes], [1965] (Box 5)
  - Albany (Executive Committee), Jan. 20, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Albany (Executive Committee), June 16, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Pin (Balfour) (Ordering of pins, etc.), [1964-1965] (Box 5)
  - Program information, [1965] (Box 5)
  - Council of Supts. Contract (Box 5)
  - Education Conference Board, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Resolution (Council of City and Village Supts.), [1965] (Box 5)
  - Program (Meetings), [1964-1965] (Box 5)
  - History of the Council, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Grossingers (Meetings 1964-1965), Feb. 1964 (Box 5)
  - Recommendations for Distinguished Service Award, [1964-1965] (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee II (Meetings), [1964-1965] (Box 5)
  - Program Committee - Ross Willink, [1966-1967] (Box 5)
  - Educational Conference Board, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee I, [1962-1964] (Box 5)
  - Albany, Feb. 1966 (Box 5)
  - Syracuse, Oct. 1966 (Box 5)
  - Time and Place Committee, [1966-1967] (Box 5)
  - Resolutions Committee, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Relationships Committee, [1967] (Box 5)
  - Committee Assignments, [1966-1967] (Box 5)
  - Small Group Sections, [1965] (Box 5)
  - Affiliated Committees, [1965] (Box 5)
  - Atlantic City, Feb. 1965 (Box 5)
  - Press Relations, [1966-1967] (Box 5)
  - Consolidation with School District Adm., [1966-1967] (Box 5)
  - Portfolio of printed pamphlets, "The President's Portfolio" AASA, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
- Misc. records, 1925-1966
  - Program booklets, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
  - Annual meeting booklets, 1928-1958 (Box 6)
  - Some minutes & financial statements, 1925-1966 (Box 6)